const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"During translation, the initiation codon of mRNA attaches to the ribosome at which site?","answers":[{"option":"E site of 50S subunit","bool":false},{"option":"P site of 30S subunit","bool":true},{"option":"E site of 30S subunit","bool":false},{"option":"A site of 30S subunit","bool":false},{"option":"A site of 50S subunit","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"What is the pH of semen?","answers":[{"option":"5.5","bool":false},{"option":"7.0","bool":false},{"option":"6.9","bool":false},{"option":"7.5","bool":true},{"option":"4.4","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"A 62-year-old patient comes with a complaint of urgency, frequency, nocturia, and post-void dribbling. He is most probably suffering from prostatic enlargement. Which route of examination should be used to examine the prostate gland?","answers":[{"option":"Cystourethroscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Abdominal examination","bool":false},{"option":"Supra pubic palpation","bool":false},{"option":"Digital rectal examination","bool":true},{"option":"Perineum examination","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is a surgical method performed for tubal ligation?","answers":[{"option":"Culdocentesis","bool":false},{"option":"Hysterosalpingography","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Hysteroscopic sterilization","bool":false},{"option":"Laproscopic tubal sterilization","bool":true}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is not a remnant of mesonephric ducts in females?","answers":[{"option":"Epoophoron","bool":false},{"option":"Paroophoron","bool":false},{"option":"Hydatid of Morgagni","bool":true},{"option":"Gartner's duct","bool":false},{"option":"Appendix vesiculosa","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is a remnant of paramesonephric duct in males?","answers":[{"option":"Ductus deferens","bool":false},{"option":"Ejaculatory duct","bool":false},{"option":"Prostatic utricle","bool":false},{"option":"Duct of epididymis","bool":false},{"option":"Appendix of testis","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Gonads are identical in males and females up to which week?","answers":[{"option":"7th week","bool":true},{"option":"5th week","bool":false},{"option":"10th week","bool":false},{"option":"6th week","bool":false},{"option":"4th week","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Exstrophy of the bladder is commonly associated with which of the following defects?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Epispadias","bool":true},{"option":"Testicular atrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Micropenis","bool":false},{"option":"Hypospadias","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Histologically, ovaries can be identified by which of the following weeks?","answers":[{"option":"9th week","bool":false},{"option":"7th week","bool":false},{"option":"8th week","bool":false},{"option":"10th week","bool":true},{"option":"11th week","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"The lower part of the vagina develops from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Urogenital sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Urogenital ridge","bool":false},{"option":"Mesonephric duct","bool":false},{"option":"Vaginal plate","bool":true},{"option":"Paramesonephric duct","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"By which month of development, primary oocytes begin to form in the fetus?","answers":[{"option":"10th month","bool":false},{"option":"6th month","bool":false},{"option":"5th month","bool":false},{"option":"4th month","bool":false},{"option":"3rd month","bool":true}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"A man brings his boy to the hospital as his external urethral orifice is on the ventral aspect of the penis. What is most likely the condition?","answers":[{"option":"Hypospadias","bool":true},{"option":"Epispadias","bool":false},{"option":"Bifid penis","bool":false},{"option":"Diphallia","bool":false},{"option":"Micropenis","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is correct about secondary oocytes?","answers":[{"option":"Oogonia divide to form secondary oocytes","bool":false},{"option":"They are arrested in prophase-2 approximately 3 hours before ovulation","bool":false},{"option":"They have haploid number of chromosomes","bool":true},{"option":"They are formed after the completion of meiosis-2","bool":false},{"option":"Two polar bodies are formed along with the formation of a secondary oocyte","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is a derivative of the Mullerian ducts?","answers":[{"option":"Ovarian ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Glans clitoris","bool":false},{"option":"Broad ligament of uterus","bool":true},{"option":"Seminal vesicle","bool":false},{"option":"Hymen","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is a derivative of the urogenital folds in females?","answers":[{"option":"Uterine tube","bool":false},{"option":"Glans clitoris","bool":false},{"option":"Hymen","bool":false},{"option":"Labia minora","bool":true},{"option":"Labia majora","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following genes is involved in testicular differentiation?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"SRY","bool":true},{"option":"POX1","bool":false},{"option":"PKHD1","bool":false},{"option":"GPX1","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Primordial germ cells first appear in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hypoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Epiblast","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Gonads","bool":false},{"option":"Yolk sac","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"What is the source of human chorionic gonadotropin hormone in a woman in whom fertilization has occurred two weeks before?","answers":[{"option":"Embryo","bool":true},{"option":"Pituitary gland","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenal cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Ovaries","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenal medulla","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Human chorionic gonadotropin hormone uses which of the following second messengers?","answers":[{"option":"Calcium","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Inositol triphosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Cyclic 3′5′-adenosine monophosphate (AMP)","bool":true},{"option":"Diacylglycerol","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"A bodybuilder wants to quickly increase his body mass. Which of the following hormones should he use?","answers":[{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Cortisol","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone","bool":true}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Females are relatively protected from cardiovascular diseases because of which of the following hormones?","answers":[{"option":"Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH)","bool":false},{"option":"Luteinizing hormone (LH)","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":true},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"At the height of lactation, approximately how much energy is drained by the human mother?","answers":[{"option":"800-950 kilocalories per litre","bool":false},{"option":"200-250 kilocalories per litre","bool":false},{"option":"900-950 kilocalories per litre","bool":false},{"option":"650-750 kilocalories per litre","bool":true},{"option":"150-250 kilocalories per litre","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"According to World Health Organization, exclusive breastfeeding should be done up to which month after birth?","answers":[{"option":"12 months","bool":false},{"option":"4 months","bool":false},{"option":"9 months","bool":false},{"option":"6 months","bool":true},{"option":"3 months","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following secretes Mullerian-inhibiting substance (MIS)?","answers":[{"option":"Follicular cells","bool":false},{"option":"Sertoli cells","bool":true},{"option":"Granulosa cells","bool":false},{"option":"Leydig cells","bool":false},{"option":"Seminiferous tubules","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"High concentration of which of the following substances is found in seminiferous tubules?","answers":[{"option":"Hydrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium","bool":true},{"option":"Calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Chloride","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is the most common contraceptive method used in Pakistan?","answers":[{"option":"Diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Contraceptive ring","bool":false},{"option":"Intrauterine device (IUD)","bool":false},{"option":"Condoms","bool":true},{"option":"The oral contraceptive pill","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following does not produce progesterone?","answers":[{"option":"Testes","bool":false},{"option":"Ovaries","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus luteum","bool":false},{"option":"Liver","bool":true},{"option":"Adrenal cortex","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following hormones is used to detect pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Luteinizing hormone (LH)","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG)","bool":true},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following cells are the most immature cells formed during spermatogenesis?","answers":[{"option":"Spermatogonia","bool":true},{"option":"Spermatids","bool":false},{"option":"Primary spermatocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Sperms","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary spermatocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following types of epithelium is present in epididymis?","answers":[{"option":"Simple cuboidal epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudostratified columnar epithelium","bool":true},{"option":"Simple columnar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Transitional epithelium","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"What marks the start and end of the luteal phase?","answers":[{"option":"The first day of ovulation till the first day of menstrual phase","bool":false},{"option":"The first day of the menstrual phase till the first day of follicular phase","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"The day after the end of ovulation till the last day before the next menstrual period","bool":true},{"option":"The first day of ovulation till the last day of the next menstrual phase","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Vaginal epithelium undergoes proliferation under the influence of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Luteinizing hormone (LH)","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH)","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":true}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"What is the effect on the levels of luteinizing hormone (LH) and follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH) 16 hours before ovulation?","answers":[{"option":"Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH) levels decrease and luteinizing hormone (LH) shows peak","bool":false},{"option":"Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH) levels show peak only and luteinizing hormone (LH) shows trough","bool":false},{"option":"Levels of both peak","bool":true},{"option":"None of these show peak","bool":false},{"option":"Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH) levels do not change and luteinizing hormone (LH) shows peak","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Gubernaculum gives rise to which of the following structures in females?","answers":[{"option":"Round ligament of the uterus","bool":true},{"option":"Uterus","bool":false},{"option":"Labia minora","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine tubes","bool":false},{"option":"Glans clitoris","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Ovulation occurs in response to which of the following hormones?","answers":[{"option":"Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH)","bool":false},{"option":"Luteinizing hormone (LH)","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following hormones are required for spermatogenesis?","answers":[{"option":"Luteinizing hormone (LH)","bool":false},{"option":"Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH)","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone and testosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Follicle stimulating hormone (FSH) and testosterone","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following parts of the ductal system of the male reproductive system has a pseudostratified epithelial lining with some cells having sparse stereocilia?","answers":[{"option":"Ducts opening in seminal vesicle","bool":false},{"option":"Ductus deferens","bool":true},{"option":"Epididymis","bool":false},{"option":"Ducts opening in prostate gland","bool":false},{"option":"Ejaculatory duct","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of these cells are responsible for the production of testosterone?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior pituitary cells","bool":false},{"option":"Leydig cells","bool":true},{"option":"Sertoli cells","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamic cells","bool":false},{"option":"Prostate gland cells","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Pelvic inflammatory disease (PID) is commonly caused by which bacteria?","answers":[{"option":"Yersinia pestis","bool":false},{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":false},{"option":"Gardnerella vaginalis","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":true},{"option":"Haemophilus ducreyi","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which is the most common site of implantation of the fetus in an ectopic pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Uterus","bool":false},{"option":"Isthmus","bool":false},{"option":"Infundibulum","bool":false},{"option":"Ampulla","bool":true},{"option":"Cervix","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Hemoglobin and hematocrit levels are at their lowest levels at which stage of pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Second month","bool":false},{"option":"First trimester","bool":false},{"option":"Seventh month","bool":true},{"option":"Ninth month","bool":false},{"option":"Fifth month","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Androstenedione contains how many carbons?","answers":[{"option":"14","bool":false},{"option":"17","bool":false},{"option":"19","bool":true},{"option":"20","bool":false},{"option":"16","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following structures is present in superficial perineal pouch of the males?","answers":[{"option":"Prostate","bool":false},{"option":"Ischiocavernous muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Seminal vesicles","bool":false},{"option":"Neck of bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous urethra","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"What is the major form of estrogen produced from menarche till menopause?","answers":[{"option":"Androstenedione","bool":false},{"option":"Estriol","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-estradiol","bool":true},{"option":"Estrone","bool":false},{"option":"Esterol","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"The prostate gland falls into which of the following types of glands?","answers":[{"option":"Tubuloacinar","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Compound tubular","bool":false},{"option":"Simple tubular","bool":false},{"option":"Simple alveolar","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is involved in the conversion of androstenedione to testosterone?","answers":[{"option":"17-hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"18-hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"17β-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase","bool":true},{"option":"21-hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"11β-hydroxylase","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is/are involved in the secondary support of the uterus?","answers":[{"option":"Broad ligament of uterus and perineal body","bool":false},{"option":"Urogenital diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Broad ligament and round ligament of uterus","bool":true},{"option":"Perineal body","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is one of the common causes of pelvic inflammatory disease (PID)?","answers":[{"option":"Gardnerella vaginalis","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhoeae","bool":true},{"option":"Chlamydia psittaci","bool":false},{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilus ducreyi","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is the most common type of female pelvis?","answers":[{"option":"Anthropoid","bool":false},{"option":"Gynecoid","bool":true},{"option":"All are equally common","bool":false},{"option":"Android","bool":false},{"option":"Platypelloid","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following mentions the types of female pelvis correctly?","answers":[{"option":"Gynecoid and android","bool":false},{"option":"Anthropoid and platypelloid","bool":false},{"option":"Gynecoid, anthropoid, and platypelloid","bool":false},{"option":"Android, anthropoid, and platypelloid","bool":false},{"option":"Gynecoid, android, anthropoid, and platypelloid","bool":true}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following structures help in keeping the ovary suspended?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Uterosacral ligaments","bool":false},{"option":"Pubocervical ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Mesovarium","bool":true},{"option":"Cardinal ligament","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"The prostate is separated posteriorly from the rectum by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Denonvilliers' fascia","bool":true},{"option":"Rectovaginal fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal pelvic fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial fascia of urogenital diaphragm","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Progesterone levels lower than normal may indicate which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Congenital adrenal hyperplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Menarche","bool":false},{"option":"Anovulatory cycles","bool":true},{"option":"Pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following forms the lateral wall of the ischioanal fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Sphincter ani externus","bool":false},{"option":"Skin","bool":false},{"option":"Levator ani","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator internus","bool":true},{"option":"Colle's fascia","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is one of the muscles of the pelvic diaphragm and is involved in the formation of the anorectal triangle?","answers":[{"option":"Obturator externus","bool":false},{"option":"Piriformis","bool":false},{"option":"Iliococcygeus","bool":false},{"option":"Puborectalis","bool":true},{"option":"Obturator internus","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is seen with benign prostatic hyperplasia (BPH)?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Sexual dysfunction","bool":false},{"option":"Gynecomastia","bool":false},{"option":"Reine crystals on histology","bool":false},{"option":"Urethral obstruction","bool":true}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is involved in the development of benign prostatic hyperplasia (BPH)?","answers":[{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Dihydrotestosterone (DHT)","bool":true},{"option":"Testosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Pregnenolone","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is used for the treatment of benign prostatic hyperplasia?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"5-alpha reductase agonists","bool":false},{"option":"Beta blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha agonists","bool":false},{"option":"5-alpha reductase inhibitors","bool":true}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Benign prostatic hyperplasia usually occurs in which zone of the prostate gland?","answers":[{"option":"Transitional zone","bool":true},{"option":"Peripheral zone","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"It can occur in all zones of prostate","bool":false},{"option":"Central zone","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following statements about the uterus is correct?","answers":[{"option":"Decidua basalis also sloughs off during menstruation","bool":false},{"option":"Perimetrium is the innermost layer","bool":false},{"option":"Myometrium is the thickest layer","bool":true},{"option":"Uterine body and cervix both undergo cyclic changes","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"The levels of which of the following should be regularly monitored in benign prostatic hyperplasia?","answers":[{"option":"Dihydrotestosterone (DHT)","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"PSA (prostate-specific antigen)","bool":true},{"option":"Pregnenolone","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Aromatase is present in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Seminiferous tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Cells of Leydig","bool":false},{"option":"Prostate gland","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Sertoli cells","bool":true}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following can be an adverse effect of oral contraceptives?","answers":[{"option":"Ovarian atrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Venous thromboembolism","bool":true},{"option":"Endothelial dysfunction","bool":false},{"option":"Polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS)","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Cystic ovaries are observed on examination. What type of epithelium surrounds the follicles?","answers":[{"option":"Basal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Theca cells","bool":true},{"option":"Follicular cells","bool":false},{"option":"Granulosa cells","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerulosa cells","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"During ligation of the uterine artery, which of the following structures have the chance of being ligated along with it?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior vesical artery","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Ilioinguinal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Ureter","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Menarche occurs at which age?","answers":[{"option":"40-45 years","bool":false},{"option":"8-9 years","bool":false},{"option":"16-17 years","bool":false},{"option":"18-19 years","bool":false},{"option":"11-16 years","bool":true}]},{"id":66,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is a major constituent of breast milk?","answers":[{"option":"Casein","bool":false},{"option":"Ash","bool":false},{"option":"Lactose","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Lactalbumin","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is the length of the epididymis?","answers":[{"option":"6 m","bool":true},{"option":"5.5 cm","bool":false},{"option":"6 mm","bool":false},{"option":"5 m","bool":false},{"option":"6 cm","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Finasteride is an inhibitor of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"17-Hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"21-hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"5 alpha-reductase","bool":true},{"option":"11-hydroxylase","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"What is the most abundant protein in cow's milk?","answers":[{"option":"Casein","bool":true},{"option":"Whey","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinogens","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Immunoglobulins","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Prolactin inhibiting hormone is secreted by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Mammary gland","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior pituitary gland","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior pituitary gland","bool":false},{"option":"Pineal gland","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is the most abundant protein in breast milk?","answers":[{"option":"Immunoglobulin","bool":false},{"option":"Whey","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinogen","bool":false},{"option":"Casein","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"What is the percentage of whey in breast milk?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"<70%","bool":false},{"option":">80%","bool":false},{"option":"<3%","bool":false},{"option":"<80%","bool":true}]},{"id":73,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following substances is usually not present in colostrum?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin B","bool":false},{"option":"Amiodarone","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin K","bool":false},{"option":"Growth factors","bool":false},{"option":"Antibodies","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following correctly mentions the prolactin levels in non-pregnant and pregnant females respectively?","answers":[{"option":"About 40 ng/ml in non-pregnant females and 100-210 ng/ml in pregnant females","bool":false},{"option":"About 13 ng/ml in non-pregnant females and 6-210 ng/ml in pregnant females","bool":true},{"option":"About 50 ng/ml in non-pregnant females and 6-110 ng/ml in pregnant females","bool":false},{"option":"About 30 ng/ml in non-pregnant females and 60-210 ng/ml in pregnant females","bool":false},{"option":"About 25 ng/ml in non-pregnant females and 200-400 ng/ml in pregnant females","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is a protein and is present in low concentrations in breast milk?","answers":[{"option":"Casein","bool":true},{"option":"Lactose","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Ash","bool":false},{"option":"Whey","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Alveolar cells of the breast begin to form colostrum during which week of pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"12th-16th week","bool":true},{"option":"25th-30th week","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"35th-36th week","bool":false},{"option":"19th-20th week","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following hormones are involved in the luteal phase?","answers":[{"option":"Luteinizing hormone only","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone and estrogen","bool":true},{"option":"Only estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Only progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Pregnenolone and luteinizing hormone","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is not a content of ischioanal fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Perineal branch of S4 nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior rectal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior anal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Superior rectal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is a part of the urogenital diaphragm?","answers":[{"option":"Perineal membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Deep transverse perineal muscle","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial perineal fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial transverse perineal muscle","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"What should be the treatment for amenorrhea caused by estrogen deficiency?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Metformin","bool":false},{"option":"Appropriate surgical procedure","bool":false},{"option":"Hormone therapy","bool":true},{"option":"Dopamine agonist drugs","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following muscles inserts on the perineal body?","answers":[{"option":"Coccygeus","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Ischiocavernosus muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator internus","bool":false},{"option":"Deep transverse perineal muscle","bool":true}]},{"id":82,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following statements is wrong about the Sertoli cells?","answers":[{"option":"They provide nourishment to primary spermatogonia","bool":false},{"option":"They form tight junctions and connective adhesion molecules with neighboring Sertoli cells","bool":false},{"option":"Sertoli cells have darker nuclei as compared to primary spermatogonia","bool":true},{"option":"They secrete a compound called Mullerian inhibiting factor (MIF)","bool":false},{"option":"They are not present in the interstitial space","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following innervates the levator ani muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior rectal branch of pudendal nerve and anterior rami of S3 and S4","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Hypogastric nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Superior gluteal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Perineal branch of pudendal nerve and anterior rami of S3 and S4","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is seen in endometrial hyperplasia?","answers":[{"option":"The stromal to glandular ratio is decreased to more than 20%","bool":false},{"option":"The stromal to glandular ratio is increased to more than 50%","bool":false},{"option":"The glandular to stromal ratio is decreased to more than 50%","bool":false},{"option":"The glandular to stromal ratio is increased to more than 50%","bool":true},{"option":"The stromal to glandular ratio is increased to more than 20%","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following can be used as a diagnostic criteria for polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS)?","answers":[{"option":"Level of estrogen in blood","bool":false},{"option":"Oligomenorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"LH/FSH ratio>2","bool":true},{"option":"Lipid levels in blood","bool":false},{"option":"LH/FSH ratio<2","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is not given for the treatment of polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS)?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin D","bool":false},{"option":"Combined oral contraceptive","bool":false},{"option":"Weight loss","bool":false},{"option":"Chlorpromazine","bool":true},{"option":"Metformin","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"What is the incidence rate of ectopic pregnancies?","answers":[{"option":"3-9% of all confirmed pregnancies","bool":false},{"option":"1-2% of all confirmed pregnancies","bool":true},{"option":"10-20% of all confirmed pregnancies","bool":false},{"option":"5-10% of all confirmed pregnancies","bool":false},{"option":"20% of all confirmed pregnancies","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Pain in the lower right quadrant in a young female can be due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Ectopic pregnancy in left fallopian tube","bool":false},{"option":"Ectopic pregnancy in right fallopian tube","bool":true},{"option":"Ectopic pregnancy in cervix","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Gall stones","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Scarring of fallopian tube leads to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Anovulation","bool":false},{"option":"Polycystic ovary syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Ectopic pregnancy","bool":true}]},{"id":90,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following forms the anterior boundary of pelvic cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Apex of coccyx","bool":false},{"option":"Sacrotuberous ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Ischiopubic ramus","bool":false},{"option":"Urogenital diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Pubic symphysis","bool":true}]},{"id":91,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is not found in pre-pubertal ovary?","answers":[{"option":"Stromal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Primordial follicles","bool":false},{"option":"Collagen fibres","bool":false},{"option":"Germinal epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Growing follicles","bool":true}]},{"id":92,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is not found in a normal ovary?","answers":[{"option":"Collagen fibres","bool":false},{"option":"Growing follicles","bool":false},{"option":"Stromal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Primordial follicles","bool":false},{"option":"Cystic follicles","bool":true}]},{"id":93,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Primordial follicles are covered by which type of epithelium?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudo-stratified columnar","bool":false},{"option":"Simple cuboidal","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified cuboidal","bool":false},{"option":"Simple squamous","bool":true}]},{"id":94,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is not found in the stroma of the ovaries?","answers":[{"option":"Macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar cells","bool":true},{"option":"Fibroblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Stromal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth muscle cells","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"A primigravida has a 12-week gestation, has complaints of amenorrhea, presented for her antenatal checkup. The doctor is unable to detect a fetal heartbeat. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Molar pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Missed abortion","bool":true},{"option":"Threatened abortion","bool":false},{"option":"Spontaneous abortion","bool":false},{"option":"Intrauterine growth restriction","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2016","question":"Which of the following is the rate-limiting enzyme in cholesterol synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"HMG-CoA synthase","bool":false},{"option":"HMG-CoA reductase","bool":true},{"option":"Mevalonate carboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Prenyl transferase","bool":false},{"option":"Squalene synthase","bool":false}]}]
export default arr